<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<class name="HEGoInputNode" inherits="HEGoBaseInputNode" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/godotengine/godot/master/doc/class.xsd">
<brief_description>
Creates Houdini input geometry from Godot mesh sources.
</brief_description>
<description>
Use this node to upload mesh topology and attributes from either a [Mesh] resource or a [MeshInstance3D].

Instantiate first, then push geometry with one of the setter methods.

This node is typically connected into [HEGoMergeNode] or directly into an HDA input.
</description>
<tutorials>
</tutorials>
<methods>
<method name="instantiate">
<return type="HEGoTask" />
<description>
Submits a task to create a Houdini input node and store its id in this wrapper.

If a valid node id already exists, the implementation attempts to reuse or replace that node according to HEGo input-node utility behavior.

After creation, this wrapper is registered with the active session manager.
</description>
</method>
<method name="set_geo_from_mesh">
<return type="HEGoTask" />
<param index="0" name="mesh" type="Mesh" />
<param index="1" name="attributes" type="Array" default="[]" />
<param index="2" name="force" type="bool" default="false" />
<description>
Submits a task to upload geometry from a [Mesh] into this Houdini input node.

Use [code]attributes[/code] to pass optional custom attribute descriptors consumed by HEGo geometry input utilities.

The mesh is converted into HAPI-compatible topology and point data. Existing input geometry for this node is replaced.

Geometry content is hashed internally. If the mesh data and attributes are identical to the previous call the upload is skipped and a no-op task is returned, unless [code]force[/code] is [code]true[/code].
</description>
</method>
<method name="set_geo_from_mesh_instance_3d">
<return type="HEGoTask" />
<param index="0" name="mesh_instance_3d" type="MeshInstance3D" />
<param index="1" name="attributes" type="Array" default="[]" />
<param index="2" name="force" type="bool" default="false" />
<description>
Submits a task to upload geometry from a [MeshInstance3D] into this Houdini input node.

Any transform or instance context used by HEGo input utilities is derived from the provided node.

Use this overload when you want to read from a scene node directly instead of a standalone mesh resource.

Geometry content and transform are hashed internally. If neither has changed since the previous call a no-op task is returned. If only the transform changed, only the transform is re-sent. Pass [code]force[/code] as [code]true[/code] to always perform the full upload.
</description>
</method>
</methods>
</class>
